<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->
<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->
<!-- generator="WordPress/4.0.1" created="2016-02-16 12:29" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/">

<channel>
	<title>Carfixers</title>
	<link>http://carfixers.co.in</link>
	<description>Your quick-fix buddy for any car problem</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 12:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://carfixers.co.in</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://carfixers.co.in</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>carfixers</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>carfixers2014@gmail.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[carfixers]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.0.1</generator>

	<item>
				<title>Authorized Service Centre all the time?</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/my-car-is-4-years-old-should-i-get-the-car-serviced-at-an-authorized-service-centre-or-will-a-local-garage-do/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 06:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=6</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The perpetual question on to spend or not to spend...

<strong>Q. My car is 4 years old. Should I get the car serviced at an authorized service centre or will a local  garage do?</strong>

Every car has a fixed service schedule for itself recommended by the manufacturer. Basic parts like oil filter, engine oil are changed in every service. But there are other spare parts which require replacement as per the schedule, as per its life and not necessarily every time that a car goes for servicing. Parts like spark plugs, brake oil, gear oil, fuel filter, coolant etc. are changed only at specific intervals as per the schedule prepared by the manufacturer. It is necessary to follow the schedule which the manufacturer suggests. For example, in the VW Passat, gear oil is replaced only during the 4th scheduled service. Service schedule for VW cars in India is 15,000 kms or 1 year, whichever is earlier. So gear oil will be replaced only after 4 years are completed or after the car has run 60,000 km whichever gets completed first.
If the service schedule is not followed and parts are not replaced on time, then it can lead to part failure and can also cause serious damage to other related parts – kind of like one rotten apple spoiling all the others in the basket. Also, it can lead to a car breakdown situation if neglected completely.
Following are the pros and cons of getting a car serviced at an authorized service center:

<strong>Pros:</strong>
Service schedule is maintained and the customer does not need to track what parts need to be changed and when.
Genuine parts are fitted in the car. This is the biggest advantage of servicing at an authorized service center. High end car spare parts are very difficult to get in the unorganized market. It is always advisable to get genuine parts fitted in the car to avoid any premature part failure or also any damage to other related parts.
Technicians are trained and well qualified. The tools used are sophisticated and approved by the manufacturer. This makes sure that the repair work performed is of superior quality.
Then there is the issue of the warranty. A car serviced at the local garage would render the warranty void. That would also be the case if non-OEM parts are used to replace original parts. Any unwanted after effects or accidents occurring due to such spare parts would not be under the purview of the company. The repair wont be covered by an authorised workshop even if the car is under warranty. For example, if a CNG kit is fitted to a car by an outside vendor, any future problems arising in the engine will not be covered under warranty
Cars nowadays come with sophisticated electronics. The unorganised garage segment is getting redundant because smart proprietary systems which require specialised tools are necessary to diagnose the problems in the car. For example: electronic faults can be detected in minutes if a proprietary scanner is plugged to the car. It will read the fault through the car ECM and identify the problem accurately. It would be next to impossible for local garages to do this.
Process will be organized and controlled.

<strong>Cons:</strong>
There is always scarcity of resources at authorized service centres due to rush of cars waiting to get serviced.
Prices of the spare parts are high.
Taxes on spare parts and labour charges hike up the final invoice amount.
It has powers of monopoly in terms of certain spare parts which forces the customer to get the repair job done at the authorized workshop, and pay a premium for the same. E.g, ECM,etc
<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/DSCN0416.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/DSCN0416.jpg" alt="DSCN0416" width="3264" height="2448" /></a><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/IMG00296-20110829-1807.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/IMG00296-20110829-1807.jpg" alt="IMG00296-20110829-1807" width="2048" height="1536" /></a>

Generally it is always advisable to get the servicing done at an authorized service centre.
In case of low segment cars, servicing at local garages is also okay. That’s because the spare parts in the lower segment cars are basic and easily available. There is less of electronics involved, so even an average skilled technician can service it well. This in turn saves the cost to customer.

However, in case of high end cars, this could be quite risky. Highly skilled technicians are required to handle the sophisticated spare parts and complex electronics of these cars. Careful handling is required for such cases, and therefore, an authorized service centre is always recommended.

But at the end of the day, it boils down to personal choice!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>6</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-12-23 06:20:28</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-12-23 06:20:28</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>my-car-is-4-years-old-should-i-get-the-car-serviced-at-an-authorized-service-centre-or-will-a-local-garage-do</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="authorized-service-centre"><![CDATA[Authorized service centre]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-maintenance"><![CDATA[car maintenance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="expertise"><![CDATA[expertise]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="genuine-parts"><![CDATA[genuine parts]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="local-garage"><![CDATA[local garage]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="warranty"><![CDATA[warranty]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_post_restored_from</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:20:"restored_revision_id";i:8;s:16:"restored_by_user";i:1;s:13:"restored_time";i:1419351513;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_keywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[car maintenance, maintenance tips, authorized service centre, local garage, warranty, genuine spare parts, expertise, car problems,common car problems,car technicians,car solutions,car workshop,car service centre,car care tips]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Authorized service centres versus local garage]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Authorized Service Centre all the time?]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Authorized service centres versus local garage]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metakeywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[car maintenance, maintenance tips, authorized service centre, local garage, warranty, genuine spare parts, expertise, car problems,common car problems,car technicians,car solutions,car workshop,car service centre,car care tips]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Authorized Service Centre all the time?]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>About Us</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/about-us/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 15:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=34</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Hola People! We are the Carfixers, and we are a group of car enthusiasts here to help you with all your car queries – right from maintenance to issue resolution. Got a car problem? Worry not. We will help you solve it. Want to make sure your car keeps running smooth for years and years? Worry not. We will tell you just what you need to maintain it in top condition. Confused on whose advice to take, whom to approach for your queries? Well, worry not! We will guide you through all your confusions with our simple, practical and honest advice so that the next time you have any question about your car, you know just the place to look for the answers. We are the Carfixers and this is our blog.

Starting this week, we will be posting 2 articles each week to give you expert opinions on the questions you may have always wondered about, but haven’t found the answers to. We will tell you all about cars – how to maintain them, how to solve typical problems, how to solve atypical problems, what to do in case of a car breakdown, how your car talks to you, how you can get the best out of your car and much more! So keep reading, and keep getting more from your car, each day.

If you like our posts, you may want to like our Facebook page <a title="here" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Carfixers/335093963329538?ref=profile" target="_blank">https://www.facebook.com/pages/Carfixers/335093963329538?ref=profile</a> or follow us on Twitter <a class="DashboardProfileCard-screennameLink u-linkComplex u-linkClean" href="https://twitter.com/carfixers">@<span class="u-linkComplex-target">carfixers</span></a>. We would also love to hear from you in person, so you may write in to us directly with your feedback, opinions, queries or anything else on the earth (well, not just anything, hope you get that :P) at <a href="mailto:carfixersindia@gmail.com" target="_blank">carfixersindia@gmail.com</a>.

<strong>Your quick-fix buddy for all car problems</strong>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>34</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-12-26 20:33:35</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-12-26 15:03:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>about-us</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Overheating!</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/overheating/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 15:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=40</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Q. How do I handle overheating problem? If I see steam coming out of my bonnet &amp; my cluster indicates engine temperature is shifting towards hot in the indicator, how do I handle the situation?</strong>

When it comes to car heating, we have all been there. It is important to take proper steps to avoid injury to self as well as damage to car engine.

There are a number of factors which can cause overheating of the engine. The most common reason is leakage from radiator / hoses / waterproofing etc. If checking of coolant level is neglected for a long period, it will result in low coolant level causing engine overheating problem. If coolant level is full then there may be electrical or mechanical reasons like motor, faulty water pump, worn out ram belt or faulty thermostat.

Overheating can be identified by flames coming out of the hood &amp; dial of the engine temp meter on the cluster

-<strong>As soon as one notices these symptoms, one should pull over &amp; stop the car at a safe place.</strong>

Switch off the car engine immediately &amp; let the engine cool down. Generally it takes 20-30 mins for the engine to cool down.

Call up roadside assistance helpline of the manufacturer, explain the situation &amp; understand the solution from them.

Do not touch the radiator cap when it’s hot. It’s a strict no-no. Please avoid opening the radiator cap when it is hot.

Once engine cools down, check the level of coolant in the coolant reservoir tank &amp; fill coolant / water in the reservoir tank if the level is low by opening the cap.

&nbsp;

-<strong>If there’s a leakage, even though you fill the reservoir tank, it may drain off.</strong>

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/leakage.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-42" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/leakage.jpg" alt="leakage" width="259" height="194" /></a>

In case of heavy leakage, coolant will not stay in the system and in no time it will drain off which will be very much noticeable. In such a situation call the roadside assistance helpline &amp; get the car towed to the nearest service centre.

The car cannot be driven if there’s no coolant in the car either due to low coolant or leakage. Driving in such a situation may lead to severe damage to the car.

One must always make it a habit to check if anything is leaking whenever your car experiences a frontal impact or if it runs over a heavy obstacle or deep pothole. This can save you lakhs of rupees because if the car is run without coolant in the system or without engine oil in the oil sump it will lead to engine seizure.

&nbsp;

-<strong>If the leakage is minor then top-up the coolant in the reservoir tank and drive off to the nearest service centre.</strong>

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/leakage-2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-41" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/leakage-2.jpg" alt="leakage 2" width="194" height="259" /></a>

In this situation one has to keep topping up the water/coolant then drive for some time then again top-up with water/coolant because some of it will drain off while you drive and then again drive until you reach the nearest garage. If your car doesn’t reach the destination, then stop the car again, check the coolant level &amp; refill the reservoir tank.

This method should only be used if the coolant leakage is minor. One can top up with plain water in case coolant is not available in case of minor leakage and drive the car to the nearest workshop using above mentioned method.

&nbsp;

-<strong>If the coolant levels are ok then the problem may be mechanical or electrical</strong>.

In this situation don’t drive the car &amp; please get it towed to the nearest workshop.

<strong> </strong><strong>Key points</strong>

-Always keep coolant bottle in your car as for emergency.

-Alternatively you could also make do with a jug of water which is easy to arrange.

-Generally 50-50 mixture of coolant &amp; water is added. In case of minor leakage in the reservoir tank it is ok to add just water.

-Always keep roadside assistance number in handy.

-Don’t try to touch or open the radiator cap when the engine is hot. Wait for 20-30 mins to let it cool.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>40</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-12-26 20:48:52</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-12-26 15:18:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>overheating</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="breakdown"><![CDATA[breakdown]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-maintenance"><![CDATA[car maintenance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="coolant"><![CDATA[coolant]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="leakage"><![CDATA[leakage]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="overheating"><![CDATA[overheating]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="steam"><![CDATA[steam]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[43]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_keywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[overheating, coolant, leakage, steam, breakdown, car maintenance]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Car breakdown due to overheating...]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Overheating!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Car breakdown due to overheating...]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metakeywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[overheating, coolant, leakage, steam, breakdown, car maintenance]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Overheating!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Idle State</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/idle-state/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 08:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=45</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Q. I am going out of the city for 25-30 days. During this period, my car is not going to be used by anyone else. What precautionary steps should I take for ensuring no damage occurs to the car by lying in an idle state for so long?</strong>

One needs to take care of 2-3 things when the car is to be left idle for many days.

First and foremost – avoid battery drainage

The battery continues to drain even when the car is not in use. To avoid this, you must remove the battery and store it away safely.  While removing the battery, start with the negative terminal first and then move on to the positive terminal. Take utmost precaution that both the terminals do not come in contact with each other. Apply petroleum jelly or grease on the battery terminals and wire ends to prevent rusting.

[caption id="attachment_50" align="alignnone" width="300"]<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/3_1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-50" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/3_1.jpg" alt="Disconnecting a battery" width="300" height="225" /></a> Disconnecting a battery[/caption]

Secondly – tyre maintenance

Make sure that the tyres are filled with little more amount of air pressure. This way, even though the tyre pressure will reduce daily by very small amount even if the car is idle, when u come back you will not find tyres completely flat.

[caption id="attachment_51" align="alignnone" width="430"]<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/3_2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-51" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/3_2.jpg" alt="Low tyre pressure condition" width="430" height="293" /></a> Low tyre pressure condition[/caption]]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>45</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-12-29 14:20:49</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-12-29 08:50:49</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>idle-state</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="battery-maintenance"><![CDATA[battery maintenance]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-maintenance"><![CDATA[car maintenance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="idle-state"><![CDATA[Idle state]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="unused"><![CDATA[unused]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_keywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Idle state, maintenance, battery removal, tyre pressure, car unused]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Precautions to take when leaving the car unused for several days.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[idle State]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_post_restored_from</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:20:"restored_revision_id";i:52;s:16:"restored_by_user";i:1;s:13:"restored_time";i:1420132911;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Precautions to take when leaving the car unused for several days.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metakeywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Idle state, maintenance, battery removal, tyre pressure, car unused]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[idle State]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Turn signal indicator blinking at a faster rate</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/turn-signal-indicator-blinking-faster-rate/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 18:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=58</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Q. I have recently noticed that when I use the side indicators for signaling, the indicator cluster that used to blink at a normal speed now blinks really fast. What might be the reason for this?</strong>

While taking a turn we always use left or right turn signal indicator. On either side there are at least 3 bulbs – one in headlight unit, one in tail light unit and one in fender (in some cars ORVM also have turn signal light fitted in them). Every time the driver pulls the lever of the combination switch to switch ON the left or right turn signal lights on the exterior, driver sitting inside can also see on the instrument cluster the rhythm in which the lights are blinking on the outside. When both the side indicator bulbs are working properly, the instrument cluster will show blinking light to the driver at a normal rate. However when one of the indicator bulbs has failed, the circuit is so designed that on the outside the remaining working bulbs will glow at normal rate but inside the car, on the display the rhythm of the indication light will become faster, informing the driver to have a look at them and check which bulb is not working. Tend to the bulbs and change the faulty ones and you will find the blink rate of turn signal indication on the display inside return to normal.

This obviously is a smart way to let the driver know something is not right with the indicator lights and needs attention.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/turn_signal_red2.jpg">![turn_signal_red](http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/turn_signal_red2.jpg)

Turn signal lights are the same lights which are also used for giving hazard light indication. From safety point of view, it is very important that all the bulbs are working in a car before you take it for a drive.

Drive safe.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>58</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-01-07 00:03:31</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-01-06 18:33:31</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>turn-signal-indicator-blinking-faster-rate</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[#carmaintenance #drivesafe #carproblems #indicatorlight #turnsignallight #hazardlight #bulbnotworking #instrumentcluster #combinationswitch]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Understanding the importance of Roadside Assistance Program</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.in/understanding-importance-roadside-assistance-program/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 12:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=70</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Roadside-Assistance-US_tcm137-33057.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-71" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Roadside-Assistance-US_tcm137-33057-300x108.jpg" alt="Roadside-Assistance-US_tcm137-33057" width="456" height="164" /></a>

<strong>Q . Is it necessary to buy the Roadside assistance plan while buying a new car ?</strong>

A - As a rule of thumb, Roadside assistance plan comes bundled as a service when buying a new car and one need not buy one at the start. However after the manufacturer’s warranty expires which is normally 2 years from the sale date, it makes sense to buy the roadside assistance plan provided by the manufacturer &amp; sold by the dealer.

<strong><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/8.png"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-72" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/8-300x121.png" alt="8" width="466" height="188" /></a></strong>

<strong>Q. What are the benefits of Roadside assistance plan that is provided by the manufacturer ?</strong>

A -  There are quite a few benefits –
<ol>
	<li>Towing service provided to the nearest authorized workshop in case of a breakdown.</li>
	<li>Technician would be provided for minor jobs like tyre change, empty fuel tank, jump starting the battery, etc.</li>
	<li>Pan India service</li>
	<li>For some cars, even a taxi and hotel stay is provided.</li>
	<li>Basic services will be free during the tenure of the roadside assistance program</li>
</ol>
Whether or not to buy this program then depends on the consumer. For consumers who have faced the trauma of their car breaking down in the past, this program is a God sent.

<strong>Even if the consumer wishes not to buy this program, they can still call the roadside assist and the manufacturer will deal with the problem, however there will be a charge for each and every service provided and at a cost higher than the market, the reason being the manufacturer wants the user to understand about the value of enrolling in such a program.</strong>

To quote an example, if a VW Vento breaks down in say, Mumbai within the manufacturer’s warranty of 2 years, it will be towed to the nearest authorized workshop free of cost. (After 2 years, the program is available at Rs.3000/- + service tax for further 2 years)

Now compare this to a VW Vento which is not covered in this plan. The customer will have to pay Rs 4000/- + service tax to get it towed every time it breaks down. <strong>Think about the roadside assistance plan as insurance - meaning if the car breaks down during that period you get basic breakdown service for free or minimum charges but if your car does not breakdown during that period then your money goes waste - in either case you are mentally relaxed since you have bought a cover for the car and have capped your expense limited to the fees paid initially which can occur during a car breakdown situation.</strong>

<strong> </strong>If you feel that your car won’t break down even once in the 2 years, you need not worry about buying the program but it must be noted that whenever the car does fail, the customer will have to endure huge costs.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/images.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-73" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/images.jpg" alt="images" width="275" height="183" /></a>

KEY TAKEAWAYS
<ul>
	<li><strong>If you feel the car has a tendency to break down it makes sense to buy the program</strong></li>
	<li>If you travel long distances, it makes sense to invest in this program</li>
	<li>If your daily travel is short distance and within the city or you don’t take the car out for days at end then you don’t have to worry too much about the program.</li>
	<li>Irrespective of what choice you make, remember that in case of an emergency you can always call the roadside assistance of the manufacturer. Only in case you are not enrolled in the program the costs might be huge.</li>
</ul>
In the end, it is really boils down to personal choice.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>70</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-01-13 18:26:59</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-01-13 12:56:59</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>understanding-importance-roadside-assistance-program</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="after-sales-car-related-information"><![CDATA[After Sales Car Related Information]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[#roadsideassistance #towing #carbreakdown #newcar #car]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[60]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Car Remote Key Not working!</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/car-remote-key-not-working/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 11:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=75</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Q. Suddenly, out of the blue, my car remote key stopped working. What could be the problem?</strong>

&nbsp;

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/car-keys.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-78" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/car-keys.jpg" alt="car keys" width="240" height="160" /></a>

&nbsp;

As long as the remote is not physically damaged, the reason is most likely to be low battery.

Car remote normally works on normal button cells. A couple of years after use, the car remote key battery dies out. Now, it is quite simple to replace the damaged cell. All you need to do is open the key, check the cell size / type and replace it with a new one. Button cells are available at any stationary or watch repair shop.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/index.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-81" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/index.jpg" alt="index" width="266" height="189" /></a>

Just to be on the safer side, and to not damage any other tiny parts inside the remote key, learn it once from the authorized workshop as to how to open the key for changing the battery. Next time you can do it yourself without needing to take the car all the way to the garage!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>75</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-01-17 16:33:20</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-01-17 11:03:20</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>car-remote-key-not-working</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-keys"><![CDATA[car keys]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-maintenance"><![CDATA[car maintenance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-tips"><![CDATA[car tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="maintenance-tips"><![CDATA[maintenance tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="remote-keys"><![CDATA[remote keys]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[#carmaintenance #carproblems #carfix #carremote #keyremote #carkey]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Car remote key is not working]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[48]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[78]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Car Keys Lost!</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/car-keys-lost/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 10:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=84</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Q. What do I do if I misplace my car keys?</strong>

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/vw-3-button-remote-key-433mhz-new-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-87" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/vw-3-button-remote-key-433mhz-new-1-300x300.jpg" alt="vw-3-button-remote-key-433mhz-new-1" width="300" height="300" /></a>

<strong>A</strong>.

<strong>Part -I</strong>

Pray. No seriously. Please pray to the God you believe in and ask him to give you the strength to damage your own car with your own hands.

Why you ask? That’s because it is precisely what you’ll need to do to get inside the car. Break one of the glass windows and get yourself inside. Now put the car into neutral gear.

Now you can push the car to wherever you want. But wait, there’s another problem. The steering is locked. It’s going to stay this way until the car key is inserted. So basically turning your car becomes a challenge.

So the only option you are left with is towing the car to nearest authorized workshop. Here too, be prepared to shell out more than standard charges since the effort of towing is higher in this case.

<strong>Part -II</strong>

With a new car we get two set of car keys. Suppose we loose one . Now there are a number of factors which makes us delay in getting another key made form the car dealer. Since we have one spare key we feel lazy to get a new one made. Secondly except the very basic cars, the charges for getting another key made are exorbitant. Thirdly getting a new car key made from the car dealer is a tedious process - they might require advance amount, entire process can take around 8-10 days, they will need a consent letter that you are allowing them to make a spare key for your car, they might have to program the key specifically for your car so they will need the car physically present the the workshop, etc.

<strong>Part - III</strong>

Except for the basic low end cars, most of the new cars come with two set computerized keys. In case car keys are lost, please do not attempt to get a spare car key made from a local key maker. one should contact nearest authorized car dealer and get spare key made from them. Now a days car keys are programmed so that car ECM recognizes the key every time it is used.

In case car ECM senses non genuine key used to open the door and to start the car, it wont start and in some smart cars anti theft alarm will start buzzing. In worst cases if an attempt is made to start the car with a non genuine key then the car might go into safe mode and will not start unless it is towed to the garage and diagnosed with their scanner. There are cases when due to use of non genuine key the damage is such that the ignition switch and lock cylinder has to be replaced to fix the car and get it back to normal which is an expensive affair when compared to getting a genuine car key made.

<strong>Moral of the story – always keep a spare set of keys handy.</strong>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>84</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-02-02 15:50:52</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-02-02 10:20:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>car-keys-lost</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-keys"><![CDATA[car keys]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-tips"><![CDATA[car tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="keys-lost"><![CDATA[keys lost]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="spare-keys"><![CDATA[spare keys]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[car keys, lost keys, key lost, keys lost, car tips, car toeing, spare car keys, spare keys]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[58]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_keywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[car keys]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metakeywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[car keys]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>420</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[perrik]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>perrik14@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>96.25.238.176</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2015-07-31 19:27:53</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2015-07-31 13:57:53</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I recently lost my Pontiac GrandAM key and used the service of a dedicated car key replacement company, today you don't have to go to the dealer or use an expensive locksmith service, check out for mor information at https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xsMEALyRm-w]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1438351073.020817;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>My car smells - How to find the source of a bad odor in a car ?</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/car-smells-find-source-bad-odor-car/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 17:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.in/?p=96</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Q. Whenever I sit in my car &amp; switch ON the AC some kind of foul smell starts        emitting. What is the root cause for this and I can I fix it ?</strong>

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Foul_Odor_From_AC_w.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-105 aligncenter" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Foul_Odor_From_AC_w-300x200.jpg" alt="Foul_Odor_From_AC_w" width="423" height="282" /></a>

Ans – There can be many factors which can cause foul smell inside the cabin of the car. From our experience we list down the probable factors causing this and then by observation root cause can be found out.
<ul>
	<li>Sometimes when the car is passing by an area such as garbage dumping ground or sewage or a heavy vehicle throwing smoke passes by the side and if the car AC is not on re-circulation mode then there are chances of outside smell entering inside the cabin with the fresh air. Try and switch on the AC re-circulation mode as ON and see the difference.</li>
</ul>
<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/recirc.jpg"><img class="wp-image-97 aligncenter" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/recirc.jpg" alt="recirc" width="290" height="326" /></a>
<ul>
	<li>  One more reason for foul smell could be the decaying AC pollen filter which has not been replaced on time or due to over usage has decayed before time. After certain period of usage, the AC pollen filter loses its efficiency. As a result sometimes it gets damp &amp; starts degrading. The air coming inside passes through the filter and if the filter has become damp with dust it will start giving out foul smell which ultimately mixes with the air entering the car cabin. Whenever car goes for servicing or any other repair job, get the AC filter checked, cleaned and replaced if necessary.</li>
</ul>
<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/ac_filter.jpg"><img class="wp-image-98 aligncenter" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/ac_filter-300x217.jpg" alt="ac_filter" width="377" height="273" /></a>
<ul>
	<li> In some cases, texture of the seat covers or floor matting could be the reason for foul smell inside the car.In countries like India generally the average temperature remains slightly on the warmer side, and people are normally sweaty when they get into the car. Due to this continuous process the seat covers remain damp and do not get dry if not parked in open space with windows open. Now some of the non-genuine fancy seat cover texture is such that due to continuous impact of seat and dampness it starts giving out foul smell which becomes very difficult to trace. Though this is a very rare and a one off case this could be a reason for foul smell inside the car.Always buy genuine seat covers from authorized car dealers and periodically one should get the car cleaned from inside as well and make it a practice to keep the car under sunlight with doors and windows open to allow seat covers and floor matting to dry.</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>96</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-02-20 22:36:16</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-02-20 17:06:16</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>car-smells-find-source-bad-odor-car</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_opengraph-title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://www.facebook.com/pages/Carfixers/335093963329538?ref=eyJzaWQiOiIwLjQwNTI2NjAzMTM5MDA1NiIsInFzIjoiSlRWQ0pUSXlRMkZ5Wm1sNFpYSnpKVEl5SlRWRSIsImd2IjoiOTRhZDBhNTUxNmQ3YThkN2E4YWVmYjJmODNhYWYyZThlNDI0YjI1NiJ9]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Transfer No Claim Bonus from your old car to your new car</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/transfer-no-claim-bonus-old-car-new-car/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 09:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=109</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>All you ever wanted to know about No Claim Bonus (NCB) on your Car Insurance</strong>

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/insur1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-112 aligncenter" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/insur1-300x143.jpg" alt="insur1" width="378" height="180" /></a>

<strong>What is NCB?</strong>
<ul>
	<li>No claim bonus is the benefit one gets in the form of a discount on the premium to be paid in the following year if one does not claim insurance during the preceding year of the cover.</li>
	<li>NCB rate is generally 20 % in the second year and it can go up to 50 % in the sixth year. NCB rates are more or less the same across all insurers.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/insur.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-110" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/insur.jpg" alt="insur" width="340" height="248" /></a></p>
<strong>How to save on your Insurance Premium when buying a new car and selling an old one?</strong>
<ul>
	<li><strong>By not claiming on small damages</strong>: There is a trade-off that one needs to make when deciding on whether to use insurance when getting damage repaired. If the estimate of car repair is less than the NCB which one will get at the end of the policy tenure, then one should not use the insurance and should pay up for the damages. Also while taking this decision one assumes that the car will not get damaged in the same year again and one will not have to use the insurance till it is renewed and its NCB is received.</li>
	<li><strong>While transferring insurance from old car to new car</strong>: One can save a lot on car insurance when you sell your old car and buy a new one. No Claim Bonus (NCB) on your Car Insurance can be transferred from your old car to your new car.
<ul>
	<li>After transferring the ownership of the old vehicle get a copy of the updated RC book/card with the name of the new owner on it for further processing.</li>
	<li>Contact your insurance agent or the insurance company office of the old car. Forward the copy of updated RC book, transfer papers and policy copy of the old car to them &amp; ask for <strong>NCB certificate or holding letter.</strong></li>
	<li>The validity of this NCB certificate / holding letter is for 3 years.</li>
	<li>Now forward this NCB certificate to your car dealer from where you are buying the new car or their insurance agent &amp; you will get a considerable discount on the new car insurance premium.</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>It’s not such a great hassle in getting the NCB transferred from your old car to the new car and you get a considerable amount of benefit for this effort. Insurance representatives may or may not tell you about this NCB transfer process but if you insist then they will definitely help you in getting this done.</li>
</ul>
So keep these tips in mind the next time you buy or transfer or make claims on your insurance.Happy Saving!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>109</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-03-09 14:39:04</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-03-09 09:09:04</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>transfer-no-claim-bonus-old-car-new-car</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="after-sales-car-related-information"><![CDATA[After Sales Car Related Information]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Squeaky Noise From Car Door Hinges &amp; Door Seals</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/squeaky-noise-car-door-hinges-door-seals/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.in/?p=116</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Squeaky noise from car door hinges and door seals</h2>
Car doors are supported and operate on hinges.  Over a period of time the original lubrication dries out and the door locks and hinges start giving out squeaky noise on operation giving you a feeling that you are in a Ramsay Movie. It can end up scaring your date and you wont be called for some coffee or me later. To avoid getting cock-blocked by your car door,  every time the car goes for servicing please mention that lubrication of all doors needs to be done.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/seal1.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-117" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/seal1-300x173.jpg" alt="seal1" width="294" height="170" /></a> <a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/seal2.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-118" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/seal2-300x180.jpg" alt="seal2" width="287" height="172" /></a>
<h3>DIY –</h3>
If you are the get-your-hands-dirty kinda man, which means you are also a real man, you can do also manage to keep the squeaky hinges lubricated from time to time.

Following are the parts which contain hinges and latches and which might start giving metal to metal kind of noise once the lubrication dries out. These parts need to be kept lubricated to enhance its life and for smooth noiseless operation.
<ol>
	<li>Door hinges</li>
	<li>Door latch</li>
	<li>Fuel lid hinge</li>
	<li>Hood hinges</li>
	<li>Hood latch</li>
	<li>Boot hinges</li>
	<li>Boot latch</li>
</ol>
Lubricating these parts for say 2 times in a year will save you a lot of time, hassle of dealing with a garage and will also be easy on your pocket. It does not take much time but yeah you will have to dirty your hands, but let me tell you a little secret, nothing turns a women on like the smell of grease on a man. Okay I am kidding, always take a shower before meeting her.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/hinge2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-121" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/hinge2-300x225.jpg" alt="hinge2" width="300" height="225" /></a> <a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/keyhole.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-119" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/keyhole.jpg" alt="keyhole" width="275" height="183" /></a>

Following inexpensive lubricating materials will be required which anyone can get at a normal hardware shop or auto ancillary / accessories shop.
<ul>
	<li>White Lithium Grease</li>
	<li>WD-40</li>
	<li>Silicone spray</li>
</ul>
Lithium Grease - This grease is to be applied at metal to metal joints like door hinges and latches. The function of this grease is to act as a lubricating agent providing smooth movement of the parts and to stay there for a long time and repel water.

WD – 40 – This spray is easily available at any hardware shop. It is used as corrosion resistant and for light duty lubrication. Fuel lid hinges experiences salty environment most of the times making it weak if not paid attention  and so it should be sprayed with WD-40 for say 3-4 times in a year. This will prolong the life of fuel lid hinge.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/FH05DJA_LUBJOB_02.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-123" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/FH05DJA_LUBJOB_02-244x300.jpg" alt="FH05DJA_LUBJOB_02" width="244" height="300" /></a> <a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/hood_latch_wd40.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-120" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/hood_latch_wd40.jpg" alt="hood_latch_wd40" width="290" height="290" /></a>

Silicone Spray – It is used on door rubber seal and window rubber strips to reduce noise from doors while the car is in motion, to prevent sticking of windows with the window strips and to keep the movement of windows smooth.

If you do this, that date will truly end up in tea coffee or me situation. All the best!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>116</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-03-23 15:11:14</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-03-23 09:41:14</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>squeaky-noise-car-door-hinges-door-seals</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Future forms of Transport - Introduction</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/future-forms-transport-introduction/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 09:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=129</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Introduction to Driverless Cars -</strong>

Always dreamt of a chauffeur driven car? How about letting your car itself give it a shot?

The Autonomous Cars or the Robotic Car or the Self Driven Car is the vision many car companies have for our future. And now, the vision is not just a dream. See for yourself – meet Mr Junior – the robotic Volkswagen.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-130" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/1-300x214.jpg" alt="1" width="300" height="214" /></a>

But hold on. If you thought this concept was the novel innovation of the 21<sup>st</sup> century, then you are about to be proven wrong. The first auto driven car was introduced when you were perhaps a kid and even a fully manual car was a dream for the Indian industry. At such a time, CMU &amp; AVL’s project and Mercedes-Benz &amp;  Bundeswehr University Munich's EUREKA Prometheus project were the pioneers of bringing this vision to life. And since then there has been no looking back.

Today’s advanced autonomous cars have evolved significantly. They use enhanced technologies like radar, GPS, lidar and computer vision. They come with control systems capable of interpreting sensory information and can take decisions on best navigation paths, detect obstacles on the path and follow signals!

As of today, the autonomous cars have been legalised in four states in the US. However, its journey so far has not been very smooth. Unfortunately, these autonomous cars have been the centre of controversies ever since their launch. Incident involving Google driverless car being rear-ended while stopped at a traffic light have piqued interest of critics who question the safety of these cars.

To answer back, car companies keep coming up with newer innovations to improve safety, introduce new features to excite consumers and lobby hard to get the legislations passed. As to when these cars will come down to India – only time will tell. Until then – here are some images to keep you hooked. Happy dreaming!

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-131" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/3-300x199.jpg" alt="3" width="300" height="199" /> </a>   <a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/4.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-132" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/4.jpg" alt="4" width="298" height="167" /></a>  <a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/5.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-133" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/5-300x177.jpg" alt="5" width="300" height="177" /></a>

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>129</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-04-11 14:48:00</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-04-11 09:18:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>future-forms-transport-introduction</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="carfixers"><![CDATA[carfixers]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="driverlesscars"><![CDATA[driverlesscars]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="electriccar"><![CDATA[electriccar]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="future-forms-of-transport"><![CDATA[Future forms of Transport]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[driverless cars]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[69]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>291</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[รับซื้อ rolex]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>brookhardacre@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>https://www.facebook.com/shinbrandname</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>180.180.115.140</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2015-07-24 12:23:09</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2015-07-24 06:53:09</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[This piece of writing is genuinely a pleasant one it 
helps new web people, who are wishing in favor of blogging.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1437720789.361228;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>What risks do I face if I don’t have extended warranty for my car ?</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/risks-face-dont-extended-warranty-car/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 05:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=136</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>How important it is to buy Extended warranty when buying a new car ?</strong>

<strong>What risks do I face if I don’t have extended warranty for my car ?</strong>

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/war.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-140" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/war.jpg" alt="war" width="270" height="191" /></a>

A – Buying extended warranty for a car is like buying a medical insurance. We pay a premium amount to the car manufacturer well before the warranty period starts. Manufacturer uses this money for his own fund requirement &amp; in return gives benefit to the customer in terms of any faulty spare part replacement or repair job occurring during the warranty period.

But just as in the case of medical insurance when one doesn’t fall sick, your car also might not face any problem during warranty period which is good thing. However the money paid for warranty goes waste just like insurance. It’s like a cover against unforeseen problems which can occur in a car due to faulty spare parts or early wearing of parts than its actual life.

<strong>The catch here is to decide whether to buy the Extended Warranty programs offered by car manufacturers when buying a new car.</strong>

<em>The answer to this question lies in the prices of the spare parts of that particular car. Repairing labor charges stay more or less similar across the same segment cars.</em>

Suppose the spare part prices are too expensive. This happens if most of the critical spare parts fitted in the car are imported, then it is advisable to go for the extended warranty plan. Imported spare parts carry the burden of cross border transportation, high import taxation, duties, currency variations, availability, etc. On the other hand, similar class local spare parts face comparatively less burden of manufacturing cost, transportation, local taxes, cheap labor, etc.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Car-Warranties.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-139" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Car-Warranties-300x210.jpg" alt="Car-Warranties" width="300" height="210" /></a>

We don’t need to name any manufacturer here, since we all understand that which manufacturer’s cars have more number of imported and costly spare parts compared to other manufacturers which have slowly and steadily localized most of their spare parts to stand in this highly competitive and capital intensive industry. Some manufacturers understand that locally manufactured spare parts or sourcing smartly will help them strategically to compete in the market. On the other side, high end car manufacturers have most of their spare parts imported and still sell successfully at a premium in Indian market. There are many reasons for that some are not in the control of the manufacturer and others are intentionally done by the manufacturer. This part will be discussed in another section of the blog.

A customer needs to understand the manufacturer’s philosophy before buying a car or its extended warranty because after buying the car once it starts giving maintenance problem that time it becomes too late to repent on our decision. Even if we can afford the maintenance cost, the hassle and the time consumed in getting the things fixed eats up your energy and time.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/warranty.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-137" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/warranty-300x105.jpg" alt="warranty" width="300" height="105" /></a>

<strong>Research about service cost and basic spare part cost from their service centre – </strong>

A good practice would be to do some research on the different car manufacturers in the market and take stock of whose spare parts come expensive.

If prices of the spare parts is on the higher side and you still like that car and want to buy it then please purchase extended warranty which will be offered by the manufacturer and sold by the dealer. It makes sense because if prices of the spare parts are higher then why not buy a cover for ourselves so that our expenses are capped to a certain limit. This way you insure yourself against paying for any faulty spare parts or early wearing of some parts and similar issues.

In case the spare parts are not that expensive then one can afford to take the risk of not buying an extended warranty &amp; assume that nothing will happen to the car. Even if God forbid, an issue crops up, the customer will be able to afford it because of not so high prices of spare parts.

For e.g,  A German hatchback which launched in India in 4-5 years back sold a good number of cars. Initial buyers faced a problem with the AC grille (all the three – left, centre and right). It was so delicate or faulty that it used to break when anyone tried to swivel it to change the direction of air which is the sole purpose of AC grille with a knob on it. When customer went to the workshop to complain about this they were told that it broke because it was used roughly and that customer will have to bear the cost of getting it replaced with a new one.

Story does not end here. Can anyone take a guess how much does an AC grille cost ?

Left – Rs.3,000/- +

Right – Rs.3,000/- +

And the centre Grille – Rs. 7,000/- +

Labour charges extra.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ac_grill.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-141" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ac_grill-300x200.jpg" alt="ac_grill" width="239" height="159" /></a>

This went on for couple of years and many customers did buy them after which company realized that this is a common complaint of most of the buyers during those initial years &amp; that this part needs to be locally sourced and not imported form their country and then they offered the customers with such complaints to get the faulty grilles replaced under warranty. And the new prices of these locally sourced AC grilles are around Rs. 800/- (left or right) and Rs.1800/- (centre).

&nbsp;

<em>Key Take away –</em>
<ul>
	<li><em>If most of the spare parts in the car are imported and expensive then buying an EXTENDED WARRANTY is a wise decision.</em></li>
	<li><em>If spare parts are relatively cheaper &amp; of local make then one can easily take the risk of not buying the extended warranty and thus saving that extra money paid during the process of buying a new car. </em></li>
	<li><em>One should consider researching at a service centre about the car performance and any regular maintenance issue and cost related queries before buying a new car.</em></li>
	<li><em>It’s a personal choice.</em></li>
</ul>
<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/2.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-138" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/2.jpg" alt="2" width="315" height="315" /></a>

P.S – One should refer the terms and condition while purchasing extended warranty from the manufacturer via the dealer. What things are covered and what things are not covered. This helps us as a customer in understanding what all things are covered under the warranty before making the choice of purchasing it so that tomorrow we don’t feel cheated that we made a wrong decision as some of the things are not covered under such a warranty contract.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>136</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-05-01 11:18:40</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-05-01 05:48:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>risks-face-dont-extended-warranty-car</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="after-sales-car-related-information"><![CDATA[After Sales Car Related Information]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[cars warranty]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Extended warranty for cars]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[60]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_keywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[warranty, car, repair, extended, warranty, maintenance, service]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[What risks do I face If I do not have extended warranty for my car]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Extended warranty for cars]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Electric Unicycle - One of the few upcoming tech toys which will make life easier</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/electric-unicycle-one-upcoming-tech-toys-will-make-life-easier/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 07:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.in/?p=158</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #000080;"><strong><em>Transformations in transportation to look out for… - (Focus on Electric Unicycle)</em></strong></span>

Transportation will go through a major sea of changes in the near future. And what’s more - the change will not be as smooth as the industry has already started to experience some new categories which may turn out to be the game changers. Transportation industry pioneers have already invested heavily in the traditional forms and are investing more in the same to expand and meet the growing needs of the people. Yet, alongside there is this new breed of technology entrepreneurs who believe that in a couple of years from now they are going to change the way people will transport themselves.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/modern_transportation.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-166" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/modern_transportation-300x201.jpg" alt="modern_transportation" width="213" height="143" /></a>

Some are thinking huge like Elon Musk’s Hyperloop and SpaceX, while on the other hand there are innovations springing up in all categories such as electric cars, electric skate board, electric unicycles, etc. In the western part of the world most of the products are already in production, in fact electric cars are already on roads and running! Constant work will go on to make these products more and more viable for day-to-day application purposes. Nonetheless, we are not far away from the time when our kids will be using electric unicycles to go to schools. Looking at the pace of the advances in this category, products right from the concept stage to the production stage, we are quite positive that we will not have to wait too long to get an affordable and viable modern vehicle for day-to-day commute. The only thing standing between such products and the consumers will be infrastructure, traditional car &amp; bike makers &amp; political environment.

<strong><em> </em></strong>

<span style="color: #000080;"><strong><em>What are these products and how do they function ?</em></strong></span>

<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Electric unicycle -</strong></span></span>

Let us consider electric unicycle and try and understand its pros and cons.

An electric unicycle is a gyro stabilized cycle which offers a unique and fun way to travel short distances and avoid traffic.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/electric-unicycle-uni-wheel-350-watts-35000mah-samsung-lithium-roylennon-1408-06-roylennon@1.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-161" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/electric-unicycle-uni-wheel-350-watts-35000mah-samsung-lithium-roylennon-1408-06-roylennon@1-300x195.jpg" alt="electric-unicycle-uni-wheel-350-watts-35000mah-samsung-lithium-roylennon-1408-06-roylennon@1" width="317" height="206" /></a>

An electric unicycle is a one wheel cycle with a lithium battery, electric motor, accelerometers and gyroscopes. Electric unicycle works on the principle of inverted pendulum system and principle of gyroscope. We will discuss the mechanics and working principles for electric unicycle in detail in our next post.

Unicycles look difficult to ride initially. But with little practice and guidance one can manage to ride it satisfactorily in a very short span of time. It moves forward when the rider leans forward and it decelerates when the rider leans backwards. Lean sideways to take a turn. It has a max speed of around 18 Km/ hr generally and it weighs approximately 10-12 Kgs. All models roughly take around same charging time which is around 90 minutes. A fully charged electric unicycle can cover a distance of approximately 23 Kms. With constant innovation and work going on in this field will change the numbers mentioned above only to improve.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ST_20150104_BAUNISIKO_949933e.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-165" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ST_20150104_BAUNISIKO_949933e-300x170.jpg" alt="ST_20150104_BAUNISIKO_949933e" width="370" height="210" /></a>

&nbsp;

<strong><em> </em></strong><span style="color: #000080;"><strong><em>How are these products going to change our lives ?</em></strong></span>

How convenient will be our short distance travel if we start using electric unicycles in our day to day life. Riding on the electric unicycle will give us the feel of floating in our own magic carpet. Its light weight makes it suitable to be carried along with us all the time. Charging time equals to that of charging a mobile phone…ok few minutes more than a mobile phone…but that’s not bad.

How practical it is in a country like India, that only time will tell because there are many factors which will affect the spread of this unicycle culture in our country. First problem would be infrastructure. The roads are not enough for the cars and buses where is the place to ride a unicycle and the road conditions only discourages more. Then there can be other problems like safety issues, opposition from bike and cycle manufacturers, political concerns, etc.

Future awaits a number of such cool gadgets for transportation. Electric unicycle is one of them and it is here to stay. We can imagine our kids using this gadget to solve their problem of short distance transportation without much hassle.

<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/960x540.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-159" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/960x540-300x200.jpg" alt="960x540" width="266" height="177" /></a>   <a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/140929112421-unicycle-1-horizontal-large-gallery.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-160" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/140929112421-unicycle-1-horizontal-large-gallery-300x168.jpg" alt="140929112421-unicycle-1-horizontal-large-gallery" width="311" height="174" /></a>

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>158</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-05-15 12:39:59</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-05-15 07:09:59</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>electric-unicycle-one-upcoming-tech-toys-will-make-life-easier</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="future-forms-of-transport"><![CDATA[Future forms of Transport]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_oembed_2105e38cce62e8ee86e06299d8d57fb7</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<iframe width="604" height="340" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7cGzPUZbZfk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_oembed_time_2105e38cce62e8ee86e06299d8d57fb7</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1431672211]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[164]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[electric unicycle]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Modern Forms of Transportation - Electric Unicycle]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[80]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_keywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[electricunicycle, transportation, carfixers]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Modern Forms of Transportation -  Electric Unicycle]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Is your car monsoon ready ? </title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/car-monsoon-ready/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 10:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=173</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align: left;">Is your car monsoon ready ?</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Check on these few points and then enjoy hassle free monsoon drives.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Monsoon car care tips which will help you to check specific points in the car which are prone to failure during monsoons causing car breakdown and accidents -</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">No one likes to get stuck due to a broken down car in the middle of the road and to make it worse during heavy showers of rain. People who have experienced being in such a situation can only understand the pain of going through a car breakdown situation during rain. It is always preferable to be proactive and avoid such a situation by checking on the required maintenance of the car before rain hits the city.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/car-breakdown-rain-fog-man-umbrella-besides-his-broken-alongside-road-middle-nowhere-35149103.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-191" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/car-breakdown-rain-fog-man-umbrella-besides-his-broken-alongside-road-middle-nowhere-35149103-300x199.jpg" alt="????????????????????????????????????????????????????" width="252" height="167" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Imagine if we overlooked on certain points of car maintenance before the monsoon, which will increase the chances of a breakdown situation for a car as monsoon only worsens the working environment for the car to function normally.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Following are the points in the order of priority which must be checked in order to make the car monsoon ready and break down free .</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><span style="color: #800000;"><span style="color: #000000;">1.</span> Any pending maintenance</span> or service related job which you have been procrastinating needs to be done before the monsoon sets in</strong>. Now is the right time to spend on necessary car maintenance jobs.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">E.g – Brake job, clutch job, battery, etc.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>2. If the <span style="color: #800000;">car service</span> is due in a month or so after the monsoon starts then get it done immediately before the monsoon starts.</strong> This will not harm the vehicle. Also along with the regular service jobs the workshop people will check the extra points which are necessary to make the car ready for the monsoon. Any irregularity in the car will be found out and fixed during service thus reducing chances of any breakdown situation during rainy days.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/service.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-186" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/service.jpg" alt="service" width="209" height="131" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>3.</strong> <strong>Never procrastinate a <span style="color: #800000;">clutch job</span> or a <span style="color: #800000;">weak battery</span>. One never knows when either of these two might ditch us on a rainy day.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Symptoms of Clutch Failure - If you feel the clutch pedal movement has become hard, or the pedal is easy to push and it does not retract or a burning kind of smell inside the cabin from gearbox side, it indicates that the clutch plate has worn out and it needs replacement.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Symptoms of Weak Battery – 1)Engine cranks but does not start 2)No crank, no start and no light  3)one day it starts and next day it does not.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Observe and sense any of these symptoms &amp; get the required repair job done before the monsoon sets in.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If we neglect the symptoms – (Clutch) Driving during the monsoon with weak clutch or battery will only make the condition worse for the clutch and battery &amp; cause early breakdown of the car. In monsoon there is bumper to bumper traffic so clutch will be used a lot which will cause the weak clutch to fail early.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">(Battery) – During monsoon, the car remains cold &amp; as a result during morning cold starting the car will require extra energy from the battery to start for the first time         during the day. Using up more power from the already weak battery will cause the         battery to fail early in the monsoon season.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>4. One should get the<span style="color: #800000;"> wiper blades</span> replaced every two years for better cleaning of the windshield &amp; hence better visibility.</strong> Wiper blades are not so expensive and blades can be replaced in a very short time.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wiper.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-188" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/wiper-300x144.jpg" alt="wiper" width="246" height="118" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>5.</strong> <span style="color: #800000;"><strong>Tyres</strong></span> – If the tyre tread depth has reduced &amp; tyre surface has become flat as shown in the figure , it indicates that tyres have worn out and it wont be effective in its function of holding the grip of the road while rolling smoothly.<a href="http://carfixers.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/tyres.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-192" src="http://carfixers.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/tyres-300x199.jpg" alt="tyres" width="268" height="178" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>In rainy season, roads are wet and slippery &amp; if such tyres are not changed then               it may lead  to skidding and aquaplaning thus increasing the chance</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em><span style="color: #0000ff;">(Note :Aquaplaning - A tyre travelling through water pushes a wave ahead of it. In order for a tyre to perform properly on a wet surface, it must be able to disperse the water in the tyre tread depth to restore dry contact. The presence of too much water can make your vehicle lose contact with the road surface.)</span></em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/aqua2.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-175" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/aqua2-300x178.jpg" alt="aqua2" width="254" height="151" /></a><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/aqua1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-174" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/aqua1.jpg" alt="aqua1" width="200" height="112" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Also if any tyre is giving a lot of problems like it gets punctured lot many times then its better to replace it before the monsoon starts. Changing a flat tyre during rains is not what anyone wants.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>6.</strong> <strong style="color: #800000;">Brakes</strong> – <strong>If you have been experiencing ineffective brakes or something abnormal about brakes like noise upon braking, carbon deposition around brakes, discs and alloy wheels then it needs to be checked at authorized workshops.</strong> Brake caliper pin lubrication is necessary before monsoon starts. Brake pads if below permissible thickness need to be replaced.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/brake-pads-4.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-176" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/brake-pads-4-300x217.jpg" alt="brake-pads-4" width="225" height="163" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Braking is required more and in an effective way during monsoon season &amp; any weakness in the brakes during rainy season will only increase the chances of accidents.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>7.</strong> <strong><span style="color: #800000;">Electrical connections</span></strong> - <strong>If you find any electrical connections damaged or some wires eaten by rodents then please get it repaired, taped, covered &amp; tightened before the monsoon starts.</strong> Because in wet weather electrical connections if loose will damaged further, contacts will get rusted causing less contact area and thus failure.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/rodent.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-184" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/rodent-300x200.jpg" alt="rodent" width="254" height="169" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="color: #800000;"><strong><span style="color: #000000;">8.</span> Lights</strong></span> – <strong>Check whether all the light bulbs are working properly</strong> (Headlight, tail light, reverse light, indicator lights, etc.)Company does provide couple of spare bulbs with the car. Periodically check the condition of the spare bulbs and replace them if found damaged or expired.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/lights.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-193" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/lights-300x236.jpg" alt="lights" width="221" height="174" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="color: #800000;"><strong><span style="color: #000000;">9.</span> Door Hinges &amp; latch lubrication</strong> </span>– During monsoon door hinges start making squeaky noise as the old lubrication layer is washed off in rains. One can easily get lubrication grease and WD-40 solution in any hardware store. During monsoon door hinges and latches tend to become dry and can also start to rust due to over exposure to moisture and wetness around. <strong>Appropriate lubrication will reduce the squeaking noise significantly and will prevent rusting near hinges and latches. Fresh grease and other lubrication substances repel water thus protecting rubbing surfaces from rusting.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/doorhinge.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-177" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/doorhinge.jpg" alt="doorhinge" width="226" height="169" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="color: #800000;"><strong><span style="color: #000000;">10.</span> Fuse</strong></span> –<strong> One should always keep spare fuses of different amperes in the car.</strong> It hardly costs anything but one realizes its importance when we need it during car breakdown situation on a rainy day.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/fuse.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-179" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/fuse-300x184.jpg" alt="fuse" width="222" height="136" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><span style="color: #800000;"><span style="color: #000000;">11.</span> Body Polish</span></strong> – During monsoon the paint of the car starts to dull or sometimes even peels off from certain areas. In city and industrial area where pollution levels are high, rain contains contaminants which destroys the luster of the car paint thus making it look dull and in worst cases peels off at certain areas.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">One should get wax polish done to the car before the monsoon starts. <strong>This layer of               wax on car surface protects the car as well as rain water will trickle down even               more smoothly and thus won’t get in touch with actual paint surface thus                         saving the paint and its shine.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/UK8-1_CarPolish-575x381.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-194" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/UK8-1_CarPolish-575x381-300x198.jpg" alt="UK8-1_CarPolish-575x381" width="226" height="149" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong style="color: #800000;"><span style="color: #000000;">12.</span> Floor Mattings</strong> – During monsoon, textile floor mats should be replaced with rubber floor mats for couple of months as they do not soak water and get dirty easily.<strong> Wet and muddy textile mats then start giving out foul odor inside the cabin and cleaning the mats becomes a difficult task. Rubber mats on the other hand solves both these problems. Also rubber mats are cheaper than textile mats.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/mattings.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-182" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/mattings.jpg" alt="mattings" width="192" height="192" /></a><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/car-mats.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-195" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/car-mats.jpg" alt="car mats" width="179" height="119" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>13. Miscellaneous Items which one might require in the car during monsoon season–</strong><strong>Other useful items which needs to kept in the car for emergency help are – <span style="color: #800000;">a                     torch light, a small hammer, first-aid kit (very imp), a spare umbrella, fuses and             light bulbs.</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>14. Last but not the least everyone in the family who drives the car should make a note of the <span style="color: #800000;">Roadside Assistance helpline number</span> provided by the manufacturer.</strong> In case of an accident or break down situation people panic and that time roadside assistance number will help you sail through the problem smoothly.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/rsa1.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-196" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/rsa1-300x118.jpg" alt="rsa1" width="257" height="101" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><em>Now, drive out and enjoy the rains.</em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>173</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-05-27 16:27:52</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-05-27 10:57:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>car-monsoon-ready</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="automobile"><![CDATA[automobile]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-car-tips"><![CDATA[car car tips]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-maintenance"><![CDATA[car maintenance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-tips"><![CDATA[car tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="monsoon"><![CDATA[monsoon]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="rain"><![CDATA[rain]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[car tips, car maintenance, car car tips, automobile, monsoon, rain]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Monsoon car care tips which will help you to check specific points in the car which are prone to failure during monsoons causing car breakdown and accidents]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[64]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[203]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_keywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[car tips, car maintenance, car car tips, automobile, monsoon, rain]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Monsoon car care tips which will help you to check specific points in the car which are prone to failure during monsoons causing car breakdown and accidents]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Is your car monsoon ready ? carfixers]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Vehicle Pulling to One Side</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/212/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 07:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=212</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="color: #993300;"><strong>Q. My car is pulling towards left / right even when driven on a straight and smooth road</strong></span>

Ans – This is a common problem faced by all drivers at some point in time during driving.There could be several reasons that may be causing this. So one must get following points checked in order to find the root cause for vehicle pulling. Good news is that all of the problems are easy, and more importantly, economical to fix!
<ul>
	<li>First of all get the<strong> tyre pressures</strong> checked in all the 4 tyres. Uneven tyre pressure is one of the common reasons for vehicle pulling in many cars.</li>
	<li><strong>Wheel alignment</strong> changes if tyre pressure is not maintained properly in all 4 tyres. The toe angle also changes over a period of time causing the wheel alignment to go out and as a result tyre wear and ultimately vehicle pulling. It is always advisable to get wheel alignment done once in 6 months and also when suspension service work is done.<a href="http://carfixers.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/wheel_alignment_1.jpg"> </a></li>
</ul>
<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/wheel_alignment_1.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-213" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/wheel_alignment_1-300x197.jpg" alt="wheel_alignment_1" width="256" height="168" /></a>     <a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/toe03.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-214" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/toe03-300x225.jpg" alt="toe03" width="256" height="192" /></a>
<ul>
	<li>If one side of the<strong> tyre crown area is worn out more</strong> than the other, then the vehicle will be pulled towards the side which is worn out more than the other. In this scenario, it is better to get the tyre conditions checked.</li>
</ul>
<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/072213-tire-anatomy-580x330.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-215 aligncenter" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/072213-tire-anatomy-580x330-300x170.jpg" alt="072213-tire-anatomy-580x330" width="300" height="170" /></a>
<ul>
	<li>Check if the vehicle drifts only when brakes are applied. Sometimes, it happens that <strong>brakes do not retract easily</strong> when released. One side brakes take more time to retract than the other. This causes a drag effect which ultimately results in pulling of the vehicle to that side. Depending on the intensity of the drag, the pull will be equally noticeable when brakes are applied and released. After confirming that this is the root cause for the vehicle pulling, one needs to get the brakes rectified at an authorized service centre.</li>
</ul>
<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/brake1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-216 aligncenter" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/brake1-300x225.jpg" alt="brake1" width="300" height="225" /></a>
<ul>
	<li>If none of the above turn out to be the reasons for the drifting, then one needs to get the vehicle <strong>underbody checked by service center to check for any damaged, bent or weak suspension components</strong>. Sometimes our car meets with an external impact as a result of small incidents such as going over a big rock or on a curved in road. Such incidents may cause damage to the structural steering and / or suspension parts. It causes the critical parts to break, go weak, bend or dislocate depending on the impact conditions.</li>
</ul>
<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Ford-Fiesta-Quick-Service-experience-040-underbody-check.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-217 aligncenter" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Ford-Fiesta-Quick-Service-experience-040-underbody-check-300x199.jpg" alt="Ford-Fiesta-Quick-Service-experience-040-underbody-check" width="300" height="199" /></a>
<ul>
	<li>By getting the car underbody checked by a technician will give you a confirmed report for any irregularities in general and also which of these are causing vehicle pulling.  This may turn out to be a slightly more expensive affair since some of the steering and suspension parts are expensive. On the other hand, you might be lucky and only the less expensive parts would have been damaged and the expense might be spared. In cases of external impact one can claim insurance if it turns out to be beneficial – this of course would depend on the severity of damage.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
	<li>For example – Sometimes the rear axle gets damaged and bent in a minor incident of running over a mid-sized rock on the road. Rear axle is very expensive in the range of Rs. 90,000 for a mid-sized sedan. In such a case it is beneficial to claim insurance to cover the damages.</li>
	<li>Contrary to this case, suppose a tie rod is found to be bent in a minor incident then it is not advisable to claim insurance because the part costs in the range of 1000-3000 for a hatchback/mid-size sedan.</li>
</ul>
<strong>Key take aways –</strong>
<ul>
	<li>Wheel alignment and balancing should be periodically done to avoid any kind of pulling in the car and to avoid damage to tyre condition.</li>
	<li>Whenever car goes for servicing always mention to check underbody which will help in noticing any bend or damage to suspension and other parts at early stage thus avoiding vehicle pulling and any other kind of malfunction.</li>
	<li>Make it a habit to get the tyre pressure checked periodically, the frequency of which will depend on the usage of the vehicle.</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>212</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-09-13 13:25:57</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-09-13 07:55:57</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>212</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Tyre Care &amp; Maintenance</title>
		<link>http://carfixers.co.in/tyre-care-maintenance/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 14:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carfixers]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carfixers.co.in/?p=224</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>What proactive measures can I take to maintain life of my car tyres ?</strong>

Tyres are one of the expensive spare parts in a car which makes it necessary for users to take extra care of them so that its life is extended.
<ul>
	<li>Maintain proper air pressure in all the tyres. Don’t procrastinate in getting tyre pressure checked. Make it a practice of getting tyre pressure checked everytime or if not everytime every alternate time you refuel the car.</li>
	<li>Wheel alignment &amp; wheel balancing should be done every 10000 Kms depending upon road conditions and driving habits. If you are facing vehicle pulling problem then get wheel alignment done immediately before it damages your tyres to the extent of getting it replaced.</li>
	<li>Get suspension parts checked every time car goes for servicing. (Tyres start wearing off unevenly if suspension and steering parts like struts, ball joints, tie rod ends, etc are weak or damaged)</li>
	<li>Get the tyres rotated every 8000-10000 Kms. Regular and consistent tyre rotation will allow the tyres to wear evenly thus extending the overall life of the tyres.</li>
	<li>Avoid driving over potholes or edgy corners at high speeds. Though tyres are designed to go through rough treatment but frequent shocks at high speeds might cause pre mature failure of tyres.</li>
	<li>Sometimes small stones, gravel get stuck in the tread area of the tyres. Sometimes these stones create problems such as abnormal noise when it comes in contact with the road while running, a pointed stone can pierce through when forced due to tyre movement against road causing a puncture and it also reduces traction. Periodically tyres should be checked and anything stuck in the tread area can be removed easily.</li>
	<li>Lastly one should inspect the tyres at least once every week so that any type of wear or abnormality is spotted at an early stage and thus can be rectified minimizing the damage.</li>
</ul>
[caption id="attachment_225" align="alignnone" width="280"]<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/3.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-225" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/3.jpg" alt="Bulge on tyre" width="280" height="210" /></a> Bulge on tyre[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_226" align="alignnone" width="287"]<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-226" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/2.jpg" alt="Tread wear comparison" width="287" height="176" /></a> Tread wear comparison[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_227" align="alignnone" width="279"]<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-227" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/1.jpg" alt="Tyre side-wall crack" width="279" height="200" /></a> Tyre side-wall crack[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_228" align="alignnone" width="277"]<a href="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/5.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-228" src="http://carfixers.co.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/5.jpg" alt="Stone stuck in tread depth" width="277" height="207" /></a> Stone stuck in tread depth[/caption]

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>224</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-10-13 19:45:50</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-10-13 14:15:50</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>tyre-care-maintenance</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="car-maintainence-tips"><![CDATA[Car Maintainence Tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-maintenance"><![CDATA[car maintenance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="car-tips"><![CDATA[car tips]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="carfixers"><![CDATA[carfixers]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tyres"><![CDATA[tyres]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_login_radius_meta</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[tyre care and maintenance tips]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[60]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[215]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_keywords</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[tyres, tire, cars, automobile, service]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Save your car tires from early wearing off]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_aioseop_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tyre Care & Maintenance]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
